Guide to the Department of Biochemistry, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Biochemistry, Yale University, records
1892-1969
RU 597
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
(5 boxes)
The records consist of graduate student files, fellowship materials, research applications, reports, and accounting books documenting the Yale Department of Biochemistry, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit.
Yale University. Dept. of Biochemistry
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of graduate student files, fellowship materials, research applications, reports, and accounting books documenting the Yale Department of Biochemistry, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Biochemistry -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Biochemistry
- Records, 1892-1969; Accession 1969-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2044.
  - Graduate Student Files - N.S. Ph.D.
  - Anplications for Pre-Doctoral Study
    - 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Applicants Rejected
    - 1965-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Applicants - Correspondence - Accepted - Declined
    - 1965-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Applicants - Financial Aid (Box 3)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 3)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 3)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Post-Doctoral Students
  - Students - Withdrawn from Graduate Study in Bio-Chemical Dept.
    - A, 1937 (Box 3)
    - B (Box 3)
    - C (Box 3)
    - D, 1932 (Box 3)
    - E (Box 3)
    - F, 1934 (Box 3)
    - G, 1934-1937 (Box 3)
    - H, 1942-1950 (Box 3)
    - I (Box 3)
    - J (Box 3)
    - K (Box 3)
    - L (Box 3)
    - M (Box 3)
    - N, 1941 (Box 3)
    - O (Box 3)
    - P (Box 3)
    - Q (Box 3)
    - R, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
    - S, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
    - T (Box 3)
    - U (Box 3)
    - V (Box 3)
    - W (Box 3)
    - X, 1936-1939 (Box 3)
    - Y (Box 3)
    - Z (Box 3)
  - Graduate Studies - Pre-Doctoral - Fellowships, Scholarships
    - Mailing List of Colleges and Universities (Box 4)
  - Appicants: Research Assistants
    - Assistantship Applications, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
    - Research Assistants Technical, 1937-1948 (Box 4)
    - W- Research Assistants, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Students A, empty (Box 4)
    - Students B, 1948-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students C, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Students D, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Students E, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Students F, 1948-1950 (Box 4)
    - Students G, 1949-1951 (Box 4)
    - Students H, 1938-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students I, empty (Box 4)
    - Students J, 1941 (Box 4)
    - Students K, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students L, 1949-1951 (Box 4)
    - Students M, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
    - Students N, empty (Box 4)
    - Students 0, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students P, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Students Q, empty (Box 4)
    - Students R, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students S, 1948-1959 (Box 4)
    - Students T, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Students U, empty (Box 4)
    - Students V, 1939 (Box 4)
    - Students W, 1939-1951 (Box 4)
    - Students X,Y,Z, 1949 (Box 4)
    - Student Applications, 1940-1948 (Box 4)
    - Available Outside Positions, 1945-1948 (Box 4)
  - Fellows
    - Fellowship Applications Yale University School of Medicine, undated (Box 4)
    - Fellows A, 1945 (Box 4)
    - Fellows B, 1939-1952 (Box 4)
    - Fellows C, 1947-1953 (Box 4)
    - Fellows D-J, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Fellows K, 1940-1946 (Box 4)
    - Fellows L, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Fellows M, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Fellows P, 1933-1946 (Box 4)
    - Fellows R, 1947-1951 (Box 4)
    - Fellows S, 1934-1950 (Box 4)
    - Fellows T, 1933 (Box 4)
    - Fellows U, 1948-1951 (Box 4)
    - Fellows W, 1939-1941 (Box 4)
  - Fellows \(Former)
    - Fellows A, 1935-1947 (Box 4)
    - Fellows B, 1939 (Box 4)
    - Fellows C, 1937-1944 (Box 4)
    - Fellows D, 1939-1942 (Box 4)
    - Fellows E, 1941-1945 (Box 4)
    - Fellows F, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Fellows G, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Fellows H, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Fellows I (Box 4)
    - Fellows J (Box 4)
    - Fellows K, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Fellows L, 1941-1947 (Box 4)
    - Fellows H (Box 4)
    - Fellows N (Box 4)
    - Fellows 0, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Fellows P, 1940-1947 (Box 4)
    - Fellows Q (Box 4)
    - Fellows R (Box 4)
    - Fellows S, 1939-1940 (Box 4)
    - Fellows T, 1938 (Box 4)
    - Fellows U (Box 4)
    - Fellows V (Box 4)
    - Fellows W, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Fellows X (Box 4)
    - Fellows Y (Box 4)
    - Fellows Z (Box 4)
  - Staff - Faculty
    - Staff Applications, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Staff Applications, 1946-1953 (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty A, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty B (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty C (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty D (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty E, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Staff -Faculty F, 1939-1951 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty G, 1941-1951 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty H, empty (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty J, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty K, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Starf - Faculty L, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty H, 1945[?] (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty N (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty 0 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty P (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty Q (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty R, 1939-1953 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty S, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty T (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty V, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty W (Box 4)
    - Staff - Faculty X,Y,Z (Box 4)
  - Alumni
    - A (Box 4)
    - B, 1933-1941 (Box 4)
    - C, 1931-1952 (Box 4)
    - D, 1938-1942 (Box 4)
    - E (Box 4)
    - F, 1933-1940 (Box 4)
    - G, 1951 (Box 4)
    - H, 1933-1946 (Box 4)
    - I (Box 4)
    - J, 1931-1946 (Box 4)
    - K, 1934-1952 (Box 4)
    - L, 1933-1943 (Box 4)
    - M, 1932-1940 (Box 4)
    - N (Box 4)
    - O, 1929 (Box 4)
    - P, 1932-1952 (Box 4)
    - Q (Box 4)
    - R, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
    - S, 1938-1953 (Box 4)
    - T (Box 4)
    - U (Box 4)
    - V, 1940-1952 (Box 4)
    - W, 1951 (Box 4)
    - X (Box 4)
    - Y, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Z (Box 4)
  - Biochemistry 101, Former Students·, 1950-1952 (Box 4)
  - Graduate Students (general), 1938-1948 (Box 4)
  - Four Ledger Account Books, of the Physiological Chemistry Lab. [includes some correspondence], 1923-1928 (Box 5)
  - Ledger, inventory of Lab Supplies, 1902-1916 (Box 5)
  - Report on the Laboratory of PhysiologicalChemistry, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
  - Report on the Laboratory of PhysiologicalChemistry, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Report on the Laboratory of PhysiologicalChemistry, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - Report on the Laboratory of Physiological Chemistry, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Markbooks, 1909-1942 (Box 5)
  - Markbooks, 1892-1909 (Box 6)